#### Contact

sullivanclan2013@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/paul-sullivanlasvegas (LinkedIn) www.nexxt.com/p/PaulSullivan-NV (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Nursing
Orthopedic Rehabilitation
Computer Literacy

### Certifications

**ACLS** 

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification (LSSGB)

**CPR** 

Certified Rehabilitation Registered Nurse (CRRN)

# Paul Sullivan, BSN, RN, CRRN, BSBA, BAE, LSSGB

Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) at Encompass Health Rehabilitation Hospital

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

# Summary

Highly qualified professional with extensive clinical experience combined with administrative oversight and strong staff leadership. A team leader with collaborative leadership skills as part of building a cross-functioning team to meet the needs of our patients in demanding environments. Restores and promotes patients' health, developing day-to-day long-term planning and management of the patient's areas of care; providing psychological support and physical support for patients, friends, and families; developing and directing staff; collaborating with multidisciplinary professional staffs and physicians.

Chief Nursing Officer, responsible for 79 bed-unit, 155 staff members, supervising nurses and nurse managers, facilitating the design and implementing the delivery of patient care, recommending strategies to improve services, reaching established goals, maintaining satisfactory outcomes and contributing to profitability.

Clinical Supervisor and Registered Nurse, with experience in medical-surgical nursing with the senior semester level critical care experience. Has strong physical assessment skills, medication administration, organizations skills, and interpersonal skills.

Reliable, an ethical healthcare provider with the ability to work independently with groups, and collaborate with multidisciplinary teams. Proven ability to build positive relationships with peers, patients, family members, physicians, and other medical professionals.

# Experience

Encompass Health Rehabilitation Hospital

3 years 7 months

**CNO** 

March 2017 - Present (3 years 5 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Chief Nursing Officer

January 2017 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Leadership and management abilities with an emphasis on the business aspect of an organization and developing public relationships.

Actively participated in nursing administration activities and meetings of doctors to formulate better strategies for patient care.

- Directing personnel functions, including recruiting, hiring and retention of staff and handling disciplinary actions
- Overseer in a 79-bed rehabilitation facility
- Participates in the strategic and long-range planning of the hospital.
- Works closely with hospital management and stakeholders to acquire the right infrastructure and resources needed
- Inspires others and encourages them to uphold the best practices when handling patients
- Acts as the closest link between the physicians, nurses and hospital administrators
- Actively participated in nursing administration activities and meetings of doctors to formulate better strategies for patient care.
- Managed programs that promoted excellence in service and safety for patient care delivery.

Encompass Health Rehabilitation Nurse Manager, Registered Nurse January 2017 - April 2017 (4 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

#### Nurse Manager

- Creating a positive, collaborative work environment
- Developing and implementing objectives, policies, and procedures
- Mandated by the hospital administration to maintain clinical and patient-care standards
- Ensuring that operations comply with established standards and regulations
- Preparing and overseeing business reports, including annual budgets and payroll
- Providing guidance to staff and acting as a resource to colleagues

Centinnial Hospital Clinical Supervisor, Registered Nurse February 2014 - January 2017 (3 years)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Registered Nurse, specialization in orthopedics

Provide leadership and guidance to other nurses

Ensure that staff is properly trained

Address any personnel issues to promote a productive and supportive work environment

Monitor patient care for quality

Collaborate with top management, interdisciplinary teams and other stakeholders in order to develop, implement and evaluate programs and services

Apply evidence-based healthcare practices and nursing standards Review patient and staff data to measure the effectiveness of patient care

Valley Hospital Medical Group Registered Nurse January 2011 - January 2014 (3 years 1 month) Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Spring Valley Hospital

Registered Nurse, specialization in orthopedics

Chili's Head Waiter January 2007 - January 2011 (4 years 1 month) Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Server/Waiter

High Desert State Prison Correctional Officer January 2003 - 2007 (4 years) Indian Springs, Nevada Area

Responsible for 160 inmates' unit. Earned Academic Achievement Award for Post Certification graduating class.

Lawrence Middle School
Math Teacher
August 2003 - May 2004 (10 months)
Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Teaches courses in mathematics to secondary pupils utilizing core curriculum and appropriate curriculum publications as guidelines in teaching individual course content as approved by the Board of Education.

Instructs pupils in citizenship and basic subject matter specified in state law and administrative regulations and procedures of the school district.

Develops lesson plans and appropriate instructional aids stressing "discovery" and laboratory learning methods.

Demonstrates mathematical concepts using models, chalkboard, overhead projector, and other standard or teacher-prepared instructional aids.

Provides opportunities when needed for individualized and small group instruction to adapt the curriculum to the needs of each pupil.

Designs learning activities that will relate mathematics to the physical world. Establishes and maintains standards of pupil behavior needed to provide an orderly, safe, and productive classroom environment.

Evaluates each pupil's progress in mathematical knowledge and skills.

#### FREMONT MIDDLE SCHOOL

Science Teacher August 2001 - June 2002 (11 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Instruct students about global and national social issues.

Help students understand the geographical, historical, cultural, and political factors that influence the development of world regions.

Lecture on the operation of political and economic systems.

Teaches courses in social studies, history, geography, American government, political science, or humanities to secondary pupils, utilizing core curriculum and other appropriate learning activities approved by the Board of Education.

Create instructional resources for use in the classroom.

Plan, prepare and deliver instructional activities.

Create positive educational climate for students to learn in.

## Say Cheesecake

Bakery Owner

January 1996 - November 2001 (5 years 11 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Responsible for operations, manufacturing and delivery of high-end desserts to top-notch casinos and restaurants in the Las Vegas and Henderson area.

- Make financial arrangements and conducted recruitment
- Build and oversee the business plan and the budgets
- Review the report of production in a relationship with products and sales

- Compare sales with intended goals on short- and long-term basis
- Make trips to purchase important inventory and seasonal needs
- Involved in the daily business of products and quality
- Knowledge of business principles, including management, marketing, business plan research, and business ethics, increase the chances of survival of a business
- Ability to pinpoint problems, take initiative, and make meaning out of the results based on calculated methods
- Ability to make provision for a good organizational structure through coordinated planning

## Classic Car Wash

Sales Manager

January 1988 - November 1996 (8 years 11 months)

Reno, Nevada Area

Responsible for sales and marketing of the multi-million-dollar company, scheduling of sales staff, staff hiring, firing, and promotions of sales staff, and sales commission appropriations.

Earned a reputation for excellence in service delivery.

# Education

#### Nevada State College

Bachelor of Science in Nursing , Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse  $\cdot$  (2009 - 2010)

#### College of Southern Nevada

Sixty credits earned towards nursing degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse  $\cdot$  (2005)

### University of Nevada, Reno

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration with emphasis in Marketing (2000)

#### University of Nevada, Reno

Bachelor of Arts with an emphasis in Math (1994)